{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is the purpose of rotating tool used in Friction Stir Welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "To generate heat",
        "b": "To generate pressure",
        "c": "To generate friction",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
 {
      "question": "In conduction welding, the laser energy is primarily absorbed by the",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The surface of the workpiece",
        "b": "The entire volume of the workpiece",
        "c": "Surrounding atmosphere",
        "d": "The filler material used in the welding process"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What is the main advantage of Friction Stir Welding over traditional welding methods?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Lower welding temperatures",
        "b": "Higher welding speeds",
        "c": "Higher quality welds",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "Which one of the following welding has less heat affected zone?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Metal inert gas welding",
        "b": "Laser welding",
        "c": "Tungsten inert gas welding",
        "d": "Submerged arc welding"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What is the typical beam quality M^2 value of the real Gaussian laser beam?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "<1",
        "b": "â‰ˆ 1",
        "c": ">1",
        "d": "=1"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "Which of the following is a limitation of laser welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Low total thermal input",
        "b": "Welding of highly reflective material",
        "c": "Both a & b",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "In laser welding, the term keyhole refers to",
      "answers":{ 
        "a": "A special type of laser beam used for welding",
        "b": "A defect caused by improper welding parameters",
        "c": "A cavity formed in the metal during welding",
        "d": "The safety features that prevent accidental laser exposer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "The size and shape of the weld material in friction stir welding depends on which of the following parameters?",
      "answers":{ 
        "a": "Tool tilt angle",
        "b": "Tool plunge depth",
        "c": "Tool rotational speed ",
        "d": "Pin profile"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "Friction stir welding tool is made up of which material?",
      "answers":{ 
        "a": "Soft materials ",
        "b": "Hard materials ",
        "c": "Soft & wear resistant material",
        "d": "Hard & wear resistant material"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What happens to beam radius as we move away from beam waist in the direction along the line of propagation of the laser beam?",
      "answers":{ 
        "a": "Increases ",
        "b": "Decreases "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
]
}





